Guide to the Farmers' Union of the New York Milk Shed records, 1939-1957.
Farmers' Union of the New York Milk Shed records, 1939-1957.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Farmers' Union of the New York Milk Shed records, 1939-1957.
1858
Farmers' Union of the New York Milk Shed.
7.1 cubic ft.
Correspondence, mimeographs, scrapbooks, newspapers, book, broadside.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Correspondence of Archie Wright, president, and Alfred C. Kuchler, secretary-treasurer of the Farmers' Union of the New York Milk Shed; copies of speeches and articles; mimeographed letters and bulletins; reports, minutes, broadsides, scrapbooks for 1940-55, and miscellaneous papers. Correspondents include persons prominent in New York agriculture and politics. Other materials are papers of or about County organizations of the Farmers' Union, annual conventions, the Dairy Farmers' Union, and various organizations, agencies, and publications dealing with dairy farming in the state.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Correspondence of Archie Wright, president, and Alfred C. Kuchler, secretary-treasurer of the Farmers' Union of the New York Milk Shed; copies of speeches and articles; mimeographed letters and bulletins; reports, minutes, broadsides, scrapbooks for 1940-55, and miscellaneous papers. Correspondents include persons prominent in New York agriculture and politics. Other materials are papers of or about County organizations of the Farmers' Union, annual conventions, the Dairy Farmers' Union, and various organizations, agencies, and publications dealing with dairy farming in the state.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Farmers' Union of the New York Milk Shed.; Kuchler, Alfred C.; Wright, Archie.; Dairy Farmers' Union.
Subjects:
Agriculture--New York (State); Dairying.; Milk trade--New York (State)
Form and Genre Terms:
Broadsides.; Scrapbooks.; Speeches.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Correspondence
  - Agriculture, U.S. Department of, 1942-1947 (Box 1)
  - Audit Committee, Report of, 1944-1945 (Box 1)
  - Barnyard H. Mud, (Archie Wright), stories, 1942 (Box 1)
  - Board of County Presidents, 1941-1948 (Box 1)
  - Board of County Presidents, 1949-1951 (Box 1)
  - Board of County Presidents, 1952-1954 (Box 1)
  - Board of County Presidents, 1955 (Box 1)
  - Convention, Annual, 1942 (Box 1)
  - Convention, Annual, 1943 (Box 1)
  - Convention, Annual, 1944 (Box 1)
  - Convention, Annual, 1945 (Box 1)
  - Convention, Annual, 1946 (Box 1)
  - Convention, Annual, 1947 (Box 1)
  - Convention, Annual, 1948 (Box 1)
  - Convention, Annual, 1949 (Box 1)
  - Convention, Annual, 1950 (Box 1)
  - Convention, Annual, 1951 (Box 1)
  - Convention, Annual, 1952 (Box 1)
  - Convention, Annual, 1953 (Box 1)
  - Convention, Annual, 1954 (Box 1)
  - Convention, Annual, 1955 (Box 1)
  - Dairy Farmers Union, Utica Office, 1940 (Box 1)
  - Dairy Farmers Union, Convention, 1940 (Box 1)
  - Dairy Farmers Union, Union Farmer, 1940-1941 (Box 1)
  - Delaware County, 1954-1956 (Box 1)
  - Delegates Letters, 1941-1945 (Box 1)
  - Delegates Letters, 1946-1947 (Box 1)
  - Delegates Letters, 1942-1946 (Box 1)
  - Delegates Letters, 1948-1951 (Box 1)
  - Delegates Letters, 1952-1955 (Box 1)
  - Franklin County, misc. corr., 1954-1956 (Box 1)
  - Franklin County, Hastings, Philip., 1941-1953 (Box 1)
  - Health, Dept. of, New York City, 1941-1953 (Box 1)
  - Herkimer County, misc. corr., 1940-1956 (Box 1)
  - Hillsdale Producer, 1939-1943 (Box 2)
  - Jefferson County, misc. corr., 1954-1956 (Box 2)
  - Kilburn, Clarence E., 1948-1956 (Box 2)
  - Lehman, Don, 1942-1949 (Box 2)
  - Lehman, Herbert H., 1950-1956 (Box 2)
  - Lewis County, misc. corr., 1941-1956 (Box 2)
  - LaGuardia, F.H., 1940-1947 (Box 2)
  - Marcantonio, Vito, 1942-1949 (Box 2)
  - Montgomery County, misc. corr., 1941-1956 (Box 2)
  - Mutual Federation of Independant Cooperative, 1947-1956 (Box 2)
  - National Farmers Union, Board of Directors, 1946-1948 (Box 2)
  - Orange County, misc. corr., 1941-1956 (Box 2)
  - Otsego County, misc. corr., 1951-1954 (Box 2)
  - Otsego County, misc. corr., 1954-1956 (Box 2)
  - Pennsylvania, misc. corr., 1941-1956 (Box 2)
  - Producers Guide, A.D. Theobald, 1942-1953 (Box 2)
  - Rural New Yorker, Wm. F. Berghold, Ed., 1941-1956 (Box 2)
  - St. Lawrence County, misc. corr., 1954-1956 (Box 2)
  - Sullivan County, misc. corr., 1941-1954 (Box 3)
  - Sullivan County, misc. corr., 1954-1956 (Box 3)
  - Tioga County, misc. corr., 1946-1954 (Box 3)
  - Tioga County, misc. corr., 1954-1956 (Box 3)
  - Ulster County, misc. corr., 1941-1953 (Box 3)
  - Ulster County, misc. corr., 1954-1956 (Box 3)
  - Washington County, misc. corr., 1954-1956 (Box 3)
  - Watertown Daily Times, Harold B. Johnson, Ed., 1941-1956 (Box 3)
  - Wright, Archie, speeches of, 1940-1957 (Box 3)
  - Young, Owen D., 1941-1942 (Box 3)
  - Northeastern Union Farmer, bound files with index; 1950, 1952-1957 (Box 3)
- Mimeo. material (incl. part of Box 3)
  - Letters, Minutes of Borad of County Presidents, etc., 1948-1957 (Box 4)
  - Farmers Union Federation of Cooperatives, Inc. - Certificates of Incorporation, N.Y.S., Oct. 26, 1945; Charter granted to Northeastern Farmers Union by the Farmers Educational and Co-operative Union of America, July 31, 1944; Farmer's Union: James G. Patton, Pres., Emil Loriks, Sec'y (Box 4)
  - NFU: Archie Wright, Pres.; Leslie (Porteous?) Sec'y-Treas. (Box 4)
- Scrapbooks
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1944 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1942 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1942 (affiliation of DFU and United Mine Workers John L. Lewis) (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1943 (Ostego Farmer, Cooperstown) (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1941 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1941 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Newspaper Clippings, Jan. 1943-Mar. 1943 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Newspaper Clippings, Mar. 1943-June 1943 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Newspaper Clippings, June 1943-Aug. 1943 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Newspaper Clippings, Oct. 1942-Dec. 1942 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1947-1948 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1946-1947 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1946 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1955 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1954 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1953 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1952-1953 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1943 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1940-1941 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1940-1941 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1955 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1954-1955 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1953-1954 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1952-1953 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1952 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1951 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1950 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1950 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1949 (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1948 (Box 7, Folder 32)
- Newspapers in Farmers' Union Papers
  - Bound
    - Farmer's Defender, Ogdensburg, Feb. 1942-Dec. 1947 (Box 8 and 9)
    - Northeastern Union Farmer, Ogdensburg, Jan. 1948-Dec. 1955 (Box 8 and 9)
  - Loose
    - The Dairy Farmer, Ogdensburg (Box 8 and 9)
      No.1) July 1938
      Aug. 15, 1938 (Special Bulletin)
      No.2) Aug. 25, 1938
      No.3) Sept. 25, 1938
      No.4) Oct. 25, 1938
      No.5) Nov. 25, 1938
      No.6) Dec. 25, 1938
      No.7) Jan. 25, 1939
      No.8) Feb. 25, 1939
      Mar. 17, 1939 (Special Bulletin)
      No.9) Mar. 25, 1939
      No.10) Apr. 25, 1939
      No.11) May 25, 1939
      No.12) June 25, 1939
    - The Union Farmer, Ogdensburg, later Utica (Box 8 and 9)
      No.13) July 25, 1939
      No.14) Aug. 25, 1939
      No.15) Sept. 25, 1939
      No.16) Oct. 25, 1939
      No.17) Nov. 25, 1939
      No.18) Dec. 25, 1939
      No.1) Jan. 25, 1940
      No.2) Feb. 25, 1940
      No.3) Mar. 25, 1940
      No.4) Apr. 25, 1940
      No.5) Missing
      No.6) June 25, 1940 (Dupl.)
      No.7) July 25, 1940 (Dupl.)
      No.8) Sept. 25, 1940 (Dupl.)
      (sic) No.10) Oct. 25, 1940
      No.11) Nov. 25, 1940
      No.12) Dec. 25, 1940 (Tripl.)
      No.1) Jan. 1941 (Dupl.)
      No.2) Feb. 1941
      No.3) Mar. 1941 (Dupl.)
      No.4) Apr. 1941 (Dupl.)
      No.5) June 1941 (Dupl.)
      No.6) July 1941
      (sic) No.7) Sept. 1941
      No.8) Oct. 5,1941
      No.9) Nov. 1941
      No.10) Dec. 1941
      No.11) Jan. 1942
    - Northeastern Union Farmer (Box 8 and 9)
      Jan. 1958, Feb. 1958, Mar. 1958
      Indexes: 1956
      Nos. 1-10) 1957
- Other
  - Book: MILK FOOD by Paul Corey (Abelard-Schuman: New York, 1956), 189 pp.; placed with papers per EMF, Feb. 9, 1960 (Box 6)
  - Broadside: #2154 "Dairymen, It's Time to Revolt..." Card entry: "Dairy indusrty" (Box 8 and 9)